In this exercise, we're going to learn about adding tables, panels,
在这个练习里面 我们将会学习如何 实现表格 面板和 wells
and wells in order to display content in our web page.
来显示我们网页中的一些内容
For this exercise,
我们将会对我们的
we're going to use the aboutus.html page that have already created earlier.
aboutus.html 文件做一些更改
And then we'll go in and add a table there,
我们会先加进一个表格
in the process learn how Bootstrap tables are styled.
从而学习 Bootstrap 对表格的 一些定制方式
Then, we will add a panel there with some information.
接着我们会加进 一个含有一些信息的面板
And finally, we'll add a well there, with a quotation.
最后 我们会加进 well 来显示一个引用的内容
So in this process, we'll learn about how we can arrange to
通过这一系列工作 我们将会学到
display content on our web page in a more interesting manner.
如何用更有趣的方式来 组织和呈现我们网页中的内容
Taking a look at the current state of the aboutus.html page.
先来看看我们 aboutus.html 网页目前的状况
As you can see in this page, we see that
你可以看到在右手侧这边
on the right hand side here, we have some empty space there.
有一些空白的地方
So I'm gonna put a panel here to display some information.
我将会在这个空白处 加进一个面板以呈现一些信息
And also, right after the history of the restaurant,
然后在这个 Our History 的下面
I'm gonna put in a well there in order to display a quotation.
我将会加进一个 well 来显示一个引用的内容
And we'll go in to the bottom of this page, and then add an extra row there.
接着在页面的底部 我将会加进一个新的 row
That is where we're going to add a table of information about this restaurant.
然后在这个 row 中 我会放一个包含我们餐厅信息的表格
Along the way, of course,
在实现这个表格的过程
we will learn about the table classes that are available in Bootstrap.
我们会学到 Bootstrap 对表格的一些定制方法
Going to the HTML code of the aboutus.html page.
来到代码部分
In brackets, right after the Corporate Leadership row,
在 Corporate Leadership 对应的 row 的这一大坨代码下面
I'm going to add an extra row there called Facts and Figures.
我会加进一个新的 叫 Facts and Figures 的 row
And inside this row, I'm going to add a table that displays some
然后在这个 row 里面 我会加进一个
information about this restaurant.
显示一些餐厅信息的表格
So let me add the code, and I will come back and review the code in more detail.
让我先把代码贴好 然后我们再看其具体意思
Let me first show you the result of adding the table and
不过在此之前 不如先来看看
the row containing the table to this aboutus.html page.
那些代码的效果吧
Now, when you look at the web page itself,
当你回到网页中时
you will see that now we have a table there that displaced some information.
你会发现这里多了个表格
In particular, this table is designed in such
特别的 你能发现这个表格
a way that alternate rows are in a slightly darker color.
相邻两行的颜色深浅不一致
So that easily helps us to distinguish between the rows of the table.
这就能帮我们更好地分清 行与行之间的信息
This is a class that we use called table-striped in Bootstrap.
在 Bootstrap 中 该功能 对应的类叫做 table-striped
Let's look at the code to understand how we go about
接下来让我们具体看看怎么
creating a table in this web page.
实现这个表格吧
Returning to the code, now you see that I have added
回到代码部分 现在你能看到 我已经通过一个设置了
another row here using the row row-content class.
class="row row-content" 的 div 来加进了一个新的 row
Inside that row, I am declaring a column class here,
然后其中 通过设置了 class="col-xs-12 ..." 的 div 我声明了一个 column
and inside the column class, I'm going to include the table.
然后在这个 column 里面 就是那个表格所对应的代码了
So to create a table, I am enclosing the table in a div called table-responsive.
注意到我将表格主体内容的代码 封装进了一个设置了
This makes the table responsive so that when it is viewed even on a very small
class="table-responsive" 的 div 这将使得该表格变成响应式表格
screen, the table will adjust appropriately.
从而如果该表格在一个很小的屏幕上显示时 它能够恰当地调整它的表现
And then if the table needs extra space,
比如如果屏幕太窄而实在放不下 该表格的所有内容
then we'll be able to horizontally scroll the table and
那么该表格将自动提供一个
look at the details of the table.
左右滚动的滚动条
Now, the table Itself, we use the table HTML element to design the table.
那么对于该表格的主体内容 我用了 HTML 中的 table 标签来实现
So here, I have table.
注意到我对该 table 标签设置了
For that, I have given the class table table-striped.
class="table table-striped"
So this way, we make it very clear to Bootstrap
其中 table-striped 一项定制了 "表格相邻的两行颜色深浅不同"这一效果
that we are using this table as a real table.
而 table 一项则清晰地告诉着 Bootstrap "这将是一个表格而不是其它东西"
Now, you do realize that people often use the table class for
事实上 人们常常将 table 标签
styling HTML pages themselves.
用于其它用途而不是用作一个表格
So we want to be clear that this table is actually being used as a table itself.
由于我们这里确实是在实现表格 所以我们做了一个声明
So that's why we use the class table here, to specify that this is a real table.
声明的方式即是在 class 属性里面 放一个 "table"
And then the second qualification that we are using is table-striped.
之前也说过 table-striped 这一项 是拿来定制表格外观的
So, the table-striped class will lead to a table with alternate
它使得表格相邻两行的 颜色深浅不一致
rows being in a different color so that the table looks more clear.
从而使得表格的内容 以更清晰的形式呈现出来
There are many different table styling classes that are available
Bootstrap 有很多定制表格的类
within Bootstrap, so
如果你想对它们了解得更深的话
you should explore some of those to understand how they are used better.
最好还是试着自己应用一下它们
Now, the table of contents themselves are styled like a standard table
现在 当我设置好了 table 标签的 class 属性后
that you might have created earlier.
这个表格最后看上去就会和我们 之前看到的那个表格差不多了
So there is no specific Bootstrap classes that I am using for
我们不必在对表格中的每一项内容 再应用 Bootstrap 的类
the table content itself.
只需正常地把普通表格的代码写好即可
So here, you see there is a table row.
那么先是一个代表着表头的行 注意表格的每一行都是封装在 tr 标签里的
And inside the table row, I have all the table information, the table.
在这个 tr 标签里面 就是该行的所有内容
These are the table headers here, so I am using the th
其中每一列又要封装在一个标签中 特别的 表头是要封装在 th 中
tag here so that these will be displayed in bold in the table.
这样会使其字体变成粗体
So this particular row contains all the heading information for
总之这一行里面的东西
the table, header row for the table.
就是该表格的表头
The next row contains
然后从下一行开始 就是表格的具体内容了
information that is displayed on the first table row below the header row.
注意到我们表格的第一列也是表头
So that's why only for the first column I am using the th.
所以从第二行开始 第一个元素总是 th 标签
For the remaining columns, I am using td to display the information.
然后从第二个元素开始就是表格体 所以我用的都是 td 标签
Like that, you can go through the remaining rows of the table.
按照这个格式一直往下写就行
And that is how we include a table in a web
那么这就是应用 Bootstrap 类
page using the Bootstrap classes.
来向网页中添加表格的方法
Returning to the web page,
回到我们的网页
the next component that I'm going to add to this page is a panel.
接下来我们要添加的是面板
A panel allows you to display content in the web page in a enclosed box here.
面板允许你将一块信息封装在 一个小盒子里面
So here, if I scroll up,
现在当我往上滚动我们的页面时
I see that there is some empty space on the right hand side in this row.
能够看见右边这里有些空白
I'm going to leverage that empty space, and then put a panel in place there.
我将会利用这些空白 并于其中放置一个面板
Now, I want the panel to occupy more number of columns.
事实上 我想让这里有 更多的地方来放进我的面板
So I'm going to shrink the column for
所以我将会把分配给左边这些内容 的列的数量减少
this particular part of the content in this row so
不过仅限于放面板的这一行
that this occupies only eight columns and
我将会把分配给这些内容的列数 减少为 8 列
then I'll be left with four columns there to put a panel into place.
从而我能有 4 列来放面板
So let me go to the code and then add in the panel code.
接下来我会先搞好代码部分
And then we'll come back and look at the change to the web page.
然后我们先看看效果如何
And then, we'll review the code.
之后再来看看代码具体是怎么写的
I have now added a panel to the web page.
那么在弄好之后
So as you can see on the right side,
你可以看到右边这里有了一个面板
I have a panel which displays some information.
这个面板呈现了一些信息
Now, the panel carries a panel header here, and also some content.
你可以看到这个面板有个标题
This content that I am displaying here,
然后也有一些主体内容
I am making use of the description list,
我在这里使用了描述表
the dl that is part of HTML.
也就是 HTML 里面的 dl 标签
So that is what I am using to display the information inside this panel.
它呈现出来的样式就是这样的
So let's go and
接下来让我们去看看代码
review the code to understand how this panel has been created.
并理解这些代码是怎么运作的吧
So coming to the code, you see that I have
来到代码部分 你可以看到我用了一个设置了 class="panel panel-primary" 的 div
added a div class with the panel in place there.
来实现这个面板
And the panel classes that I am using is panel and panel-primary.
注意其中 panel-primary 是用来 定制该面板的颜色的
So that is the reason why the panel itself is displayed in blue color,
这就是为什么我们的面板是蓝色的
because I am using panel-primary color there.
因为我用的是 primary
Inside the panel, you see that I have two divs here.
然后在这个 div 下面 你可以看到我放了两个 div
The first div is a panel-heading,
我对第一个设置了 class="panel-heading"
so that is what contains the heading that I am using for the panel.
意味着该 div 代表着该面板的标题
So in here I define the panel-title as an h3 class here,
所以在这个 div 里面我用了一个设置了 class="panel-title" 的 h3 标签
so that will be displayed in the panel-heading.
然后 h3 标签里面的内容 即是该面板的标题内容
Down below here, I have the panel-body.
我对第二个 div 则设置了 class="panel-body"
So this is where the content of the panel has been enclosed.
这其中的内容将会是该面板的主体内容
Now, looking at the content here, you see that I have a description list here, a dl.
你可以看到我用了描述表 也就是 dl 标签 来作为主体内容的表现
And the class that I am using for this is dl-horizontal.
我对 dl 标签 设置了 class="dl-horizontal"
What this means is that in the description list,
意味着这个描述表的内容是
the term is displayed on the left side and the actual description of the term
从左往右来看的
is displayed on the right side in the same horizontal line.
项目在左边 描述在右边
So here, I have the first group here,
描述表中的内容是一组一组的 每一组包含一个项目和一个描述
so I have the dt that I am using to specify started.
项目要用 dt封装
Then I am using the dd to specify what goes into the description.
描述则要用 dd 来封装
And similarly, repeating dt and dd here for the second line there, and so on.
一个 dt 对应一个 dd dt 和 dd 加起来是为一组
So I have four of these enclosed inside of this dl class here.
所以你可以看到我在这
So that is what creates the content
重复写了四个 dt 和 dd
of this panel that is being displayed in the web page.
是故在面板里面 我们能看到四组内容
Taking one final look at the panel, you see that now,
在解释完代码的作用后
the panel head is being displayed here on the top.
让我们回来再看一下我们的面板
And then the contents of the panel, the dl,
并看看其实际表现是否 和我刚才所说的一致
is being displayed inside the panel here.
事实上 这个面板确实有一个蓝色的标题 然后主体内容里面确实有四组数据
Panels can be used to highlight pieces of information on your web page.
面板通常用于强调 你网页中的某些信息
So this is a very interesting component that is useful for
我认为这是一个 非常有趣且实用的组件
certain parts of our web page and design.
在我们设计网页时 不妨常常考虑一下能否使用它吧
The last component that I'm going to add to this web page is a well.
我们最后要实现的组件就是 well 了
Now, I'm going to put a well here in this row to display a quotation.
我将会在这一行这里放一个 well 来显示一个引用的句子
Now, this quotation I am going to make use of the blockquotethat is available for
同时 我会用 Bootstrap
typography in Bootstrap to style that particular well.
来定制这个引用和这个 well
Let me add in the code, and then we'll come back to look at the web page itself.
让我把代码搞好 然后来看看效果吧
Coming back to the web page, now you can see the use of a well on the web page.
那么这就是使用 well 的效果
Inside the well, now I have a quotation which I am using
在这个 well 里面 我放了一个引用的句子
the blockquote typography support in Bootstrap to style.
同时 我用了 Bootstrap 里面的 blockquote 来定制这个引用以及这个 well
So when I use a blockquote,
当我使用 blockquote 时
the blockquote will put a vertical bar to the left side of this quotation.
左边这里就会有一个竖杠
And in addition, I am using some additional features of
当然 blockquote 的功用不限于此
the blockquote in order to display the actual content here.
接下来就让我们看看代码
Let's go and look at the code for creating the well and the quotation here.
并学习如何实现这么一个 well 吧
Now coming back to the code here,
回到代码部分
the well is created by using a div for which I am specifying the class as well.
你可以看到我用了一个设置了 class="well" 的 div 来实现 well
I can even specify the size of the well as well followed
如果你想定制该 well 的大小的话 只需要在 class 属性中
by well-lg or well-sm for large and small wells.
追加诸如 well-lg, well-xm 这样的类即可
Or, if I don't specify the size, it'll be the default size well.
如果不指定 well 的大小的话 那么它就会使用默认的 well 的大小
In this example, I am using a default size well here.
我就是这样做的
Now, inside the well, I can enclose whatever content that I wish to.
然后在这个 div 里面 你可以封装进任何内容
So inside the well, I am using a blockquote to enclose the quotation there.
我在这则是用了一个 blockquote 来封装一个引用的句子
Now if I use a blockquote and put some content inside the blockquote,
正如我之前所说 用了 blockquote 之后 其中的内容的左边将会有一个竖杠
what Bootstrap will do is to display a vertical bar to the left hand side
这是 Bootstrap 帮你做的一件事
of the blockquote to highlight that as a quotation on the screen.
这在一定程度上起到了高亮的作用
Now inside the blockquote,
然后在这个 blockquote 里面
you see that I have a p element here which encloses the actual quotation.
你可以看到我用了一个 p 标签 来封装我引用的那个句子
And then in addition, I am making use of the footer here.
接着我还用了一个 footer 标签
This footer inside a blockquote allows me to specify
在其中放的则是说那个句子的人
the author, or the person who said the quotation.
在这个栗子里 说这句话的人
So in this case, this quotation was by Yogi Berra,
是一个叫 Yogi Berra 的人
which I found to be funny enough to include in the web page.
我觉得他说的这句话足够有趣 所以我就引用了它
And also, I can use this cite
你可以看到我还用了一个 cite 标签
tag to display the source of this information.
这将会将样式定制得更好看一些
So here, I say cite and then I say the title as source title.
注意到我设置了 title="Source Title"
And then, I specify the information inside there.
然后将对 Yogi Berra 的描述放了进去
So this will be displayed as the source of this quotation.
这些设置将会使这些文字的样式 和平时我们看到的其他网站上的引用的样式一致
Coming back to the web page, now you can see how this well and
回到我们的网页 并看一看这个 well 的表现
the quotation inside the well have been created using the well class and
你可以看到里面这个引用的格式相当好看 而这是通过应用 well 和 blockquote 之后
the blockquote class in Bootstrap.
Bootstrap 来帮我们做好的
So this completes this exercise.
以上 我们完成了这次练习
So in this exercise, we have looked at the use of tables,
在这个练习里 我们学习了如何实现 表格 面板和 well
panels, and wells in displaying content on our web page.
以呈现我们网页上的一些内容
Now, you can make use of these components at many other locations on your web page,
事实上 这些组件的应用场合非常多 应用它们的方式也有很多
depending on what you're trying to display there.
在这个练习里面 我们只是说到了其中的一部分 来让你对它们有个初步的了解
But, this is just one example to illustrate how we can leverage
基于你的需要 你完全可以在 更实际 更复杂的情境中
these components to display content on our web page.
利用它们来解决问题 【翻译 - Carefree0910】